# MOMOH ABDUL JABBAR Web Developer

- momohabduljabbar@gmail.com
- +2347066986305
- Suncity estate, Abuja, Nigeria.
- **1** 01/02/1995
- Nigerian
- Single
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/momoh-abdul-jabbar-183260161
- https://medium.com/@momohabduljabbar
- ★ https://twitter.com/NIGERIAN\_KING2?s=09
- Male
- ▼ VINTAGE\_JAB#4494
- github.com/jabbarlee
- https://stackoverflow.com/users/19784453/jabbarlee?tab=profile
- https://jabbar-portfolio.netlify.app

#### **Profile**

I am a web3 enthusiast, digital marketer, web developer, team builder.

I will use my qualities and skills to promote any organization or body as well as contribute tremendously to the strategic growth and development of the establishment where the set aims and objectives would be exceeded by my expertise and willingness to learn and improve. Here is my Portfolio website https://jabbar-portfolio.netlify.app 🗈

## **Professional Experience**

02/2022 - 06/2022

#### WEB DEVELOPER INTERN, woof Solana

Working together with the team and learning from them about Web development.

 Learning the best tools needed in software development like react, nextJS etc. .As well as web3 development and how it was used in developing the dex and other aspects of woof Solana

2021

remote, remote

#### **WEB DEVELOPER FREELANCER**

- Myself together with other freelancers developed an e commerce app for a private company using the mern stack. it was an incredible experience to learn and skill up.
- i was part of the developer who created and later managed the backend of brainfield college in Nigeria. the skills used include node js, mongo db and express.



# 07/2018 - 01/2019 ABUJA, NIGERIA

#### WEB DEVELOPER/SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETER THRIVE DIGITAL

Working at thrive digital taught me a lot about digital marketing and software development I learnt the following:

- Html, CSS and JavaScript and worked partly in the modifications of the companies website at the time.
- · Content marketing
- Using mobile phones or small gadgets to grow business
- · Strategy and planning
- · Email marketing

#### 2017

MINNA, NIGER STATE, NIGERIA

## MINISTRY OF WOMEN'S AFFAIRS MINNA NIGER STATE, Mr Sulieman

- In charge of documenting issues relating to women in Niger state, e.g illnesses like breast cancer.
- Computer software installations
- Computer maintenance.

#### 2016

AUCHI, EDO, NIGERIA

## MANAGEMENT AND INFORMATION SYSTEM UNIT(MIS), Mr kester O Omoregie

I was instructed to keep track of the following

- Record keeping and management of school MIS records
- Examining data processing /Analysis.

#### 2016

Abuja, Nigeria

#### INDUSTRIAL TRAINING AT THE CENTRAL BANK OF NIGERIA (CBN),

Mr kazeem, Mr chima.

My time in the central bank of Nigeria Was Amazing i was In charge of

- hardware maintenance including printers, monitors etc.
- Software installations
   I was part of the I.T personnels who installed new software on the computers

for both new and active members on each departments in the central bank of Nigeria.

 Network administrator
 I was in charge of installing, configuring, mai and optimization of networks and communication links.

## **Projects**

01/2023

## **MEDIUM CLONE WEBSITE,** Medium app building challenge □

Medium is a platform i love alot. This app was built using firebase, tailwind css, html. it supports user authentication and an identical user interface as the origin medium app.

I came about builing this web app as a challenge from a friend who said i can never build a web app which looks like medium app visually **JABBAR'S BLOG,** favourite blog for everything information □

I had a lot of fun time creating my personal Blog. i am a someone who does not like to miss out in some of the most important information around so I thought why not create a blog that others can also benefit from.

This is my official blog, where I share everything about Information, ranging

from tech, politics ,religion, lifestyle. i created this using nextjs,

tailwindcss, sanity and hosted on varcel.

11/2022 PIZZA ORDERING APP ☑

I love pizza's . Who doesn't love pizza? I was learning framer motion and i taught to myself why not create a pizza related app using the knowledge I have from framer motion and react.js. It was created using html, CSS and framer

motion and deployed on netlify.

2022 **SATISFACTION EATERY** ☑

This is my first trial to using Tailwind css. i wanted to build a simple responsive webpage. This page was built with only tailwind css, html and svg images.

#### **Skills**

Javascript React.js

Node.js Html

Css React redux

GraphQL Tailwind css

Next.js Digital marketing

Discord Defi and nft moderator

Content marketing,

Discord Defi and nft moderator search engine optimisation,

framer-motion

### **Certificates**

**TypeScript** 

- Google digital skills for Africa □
- WAEC, West African Examination Council
- World class ict solutions, Web development
- The IC3 certification Digital Literacy certification

email marketing, social media marketing.

- NABTED Nation Business and Technical Examination Board
- World class ict solutions, oracle database management

#### Languages

#### **English language**

I speak good English that in turn help me in facilitating good intelligent conversations.

# **Interests**

Coding, reading, body building, watching movies, video games, problem solving.

# References

**MR Kester O. Omoregie**, *Head of Department computer science, school of I. C. T*, Auchi polytechnic 08034305705, 07030989568

**Mrs.Evenlyn Oduntan**, *Director*, *M. I. S unit.*, Auchi polytechnic 07031194549,07084792291

**Dr Opeyemi Adeyemo**, *Lecturer, Department of computer science*, Afe Babalola University 08121592400

## **Education**

1999 – 2005 Edo state, Nigeria	First school leaving certificate, Auchi polytechnic Primary school.
2007 – 2012 Edo state, Nigeria	West African senior school Certificate. Six credits.,  Auchi Polytechnic Secondary school
2013 – 2016 Ekiti State, Nigeria	B.s.c (Hons) computer science., Afe babalola university
2020 – present Ondo State, Nigeria	Masters Degree (MSC), Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba